(THEME MUSIC PLAYING)
Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.OpenSubtitles.org today
BOY: Mister. Mister?
WOMAN ON PA:
Ladies and gentlemen,
welcome to San Jose
International Airport.
(INDISTINCT CHATTERING)
(VEHICLE BEEPING)
(WHEELS CLATTERING)
(MACHINE WHIRRING)
Watch out!
- Adam!
- ADAM'S FATHER: Adam!
Oh, my God!
Adam! Somebody call 911!
(ADAM'S MOTHER CRYING)
Oh, my God.
I'm a doctor. Let me take
a look. Let me take a look.
His jugular vein's been cut.
Does anyone have a clean cloth?
- Please, someone.
- I have a fresh change of clothes
- in my bag.
- That's great.
You're killing him.
I'm saving his life.
He was bleeding out.
You have it in the wrong place.
I think I remember
enough of Anatomy 101
to know where
the jugular vein is.
You would be in the right
place if he were an adult.
He's not an adult. He is a boy,
which means you're also
putting pressure on his trachea,
which means he's
not currently breathing.
You have to put the
pressure higher up.
There.
Oh. (GASPS IN RELIEF)
(ALL GASP)
There's some
glass. He'll be fine.
Who are you?
Hello. I'm Dr. Shaun Murphy.
I'm a surgical resident at San
Jose Saint Bonaventure Hospital.
Autism, a mental condition
characterized by difficulty
in communicating and using
language and abstract concepts.
That's the definition.
Does it sound like I'm
describing a surgeon?
He's not Rain Man.
He's high-functioning. He's
capable of living on his own,
capable of managing
his own affairs.
"High-functioning"? Is that
our new hiring standard?
If it were, you
wouldn't be here.
I'm sorry. Is this really
necessary? Really?
A special meeting of the board of
directors, as much as I love you all,
questioning one of my hiring
decisions? Did you bother to look up
the definition of "president" while
you were skimming the dictionary?
You're hiring him to be a
surgical resident, my department,
over my objections.
Marcus, stop making
everything so personal.
I made it personal?
You've wanted his job since day
one. Everyone in this room knows that.
And, Aaron, yes,
this is your hospital,
but the money it takes to run it
comes from the foundation I control,
so let's all play
nice, shall we?
Stop acting like you're stunned
that you're standing there.
You tried to slip one past us.
I vetted him like I would
any other candidate.
And you genuinely thought
that his board wouldn't
reasonably have any doubts
about hiring a surgeon who's
been diagnosed with autism?
So justify your decision.
I met Shaun Murphy
when he was 14 years old.
I was living in Wyoming at
the time. He was, and he still is,
an extraordinary young man.
Yes, he has autism, but he
also has savant syndrome,
genius-level skills in several
areas. He has almost perfect recall.
He has spatial intelligence, and
he sees things and analyzes things
in ways that are
just remarkable,
in ways that we can't
even begin to understand.
Those are assets.
Undeniable assets
for any doctor,
particularly a surgeon.
I mean, you've known
him since he was 14.
You care about him.
He's like a son to you.
Dr. Andrews, your wife is
gonna be very upset with you.
If you're trying to turn
this into a nepotism case,
we're gonna have to fire her
idiot nephew from bookkeeping.
(ALL CHUCKLING)
(WOMAN ANNOUNCING ON PA)
Hey.
Sorry. You seen Claire?
Would you turn off the light?
Sure. You seen Claire?
Why? Would you
turn off the light?
Melendez wants
to operate on 104,
but Claire hasn't
gotten informed consent.
And she's ignoring her
page. You seen her?
No. Now go away,
and turn off the light.
Sure.
(CLAIRE LAUGHS)
They need you to...
I heard.
She's such a bitch.
No. She just doesn't like you.
It's kind of silly, isn't it?
Um, maybe. To say for sure,
I'd need to know what
it is you're talking about.
Us.
Well, not silly at all.
Quite a bit of fun, actually.
I meant that we're
hiding it, our relationship.
Hmm.
Well, Jared,
we don't have a
relationship. We have sex.
But, if you wanna tell people
that you're screwing me, go for it.
The veins in the boy's
left arm are popping.
Is that bad?
I don't see...
Intrathoracic pressure.
No. His chest is
rising. He's breathing.
No, the chest is
moving paradoxically.
The left lung is in distress.
Yes.
Who here has a sharp knife,
blade, five inches or longer?
Nobody?
You should start
artificial respiration.
He's going to stop
breathing very soon.
CALLUM: I feel fine.
Dr. Melendez would like
to do the surgery today.
You need bypass
surgery, quite urgently.
Would you please
sign the consent?
No.
You're scared.
I'm not scared.
Well, you should be. We're
gonna cut your chest open.
We're gonna stop your
heart, repair it, and restart it.
You're seriously telling me
that that doesn't scare you?
I just want a second opinion.
Callum, yesterday,
your life was perfect.
You were playing tennis.
You had a big anniversary.
Today, you're lying in a hospital
bed trying to figure out the best way
to say goodbye, maybe
forever, to your teenage children.
Why are you doing this?
Because I can't deal with lies.
If you lie to me, my
answers won't help you.
But, if you're scared,
I can help you.
I'm scared.
Okay.
You can't be back here.
I need a knife.
Where do you keep the knives
people forget they're traveling with?
A knife? Sure. Anything else?
I do also need a
narrow six-foot tube
and high-proof alcohol and
gloves and baggage-handling tape,
but I'm gonna get the
alcohol from the duty-free store
and the tube from the
back of the soda machine.
I wish you all the luck with that,
but I'm not gonna give you a knife.
I need a knife. It's very...
There is a medical emergency.
There's a medical
emergency. That one.
That one right near the top looks
very sharp. Would you get it for me?
I'm not gonna give
you a knife. I'll ask...
There's not the time.
Weapon! Weapon!
Move! Get out of the way!
Drop it.
You idiot! You're lucky
we didn't just shoot.
No! He's trying to
save my son's life.
You get that consent on 104?
Well, I made him a deal.
He's got a meeting with Dr. Max
from Psychiatry at 6:00.
We'll get the consent by 8:00.
We can operate first
thing in the morning.
You did pass Anatomy,
right, Dr. Browne?
His problem's in his
heart, not his head.
He's not psychologically ready
for surgery. He will be soon.
He is physically
ready, so get consent.
We're prepping OR-6 now.
Do I need to cite you the 17
studies that show a correlation
between attitude and
outcome in surgical patients?
Do I need to remind you
that I am your superior?
You do know what the
opposite of superior is, right?
Subordinate. It doesn't...
Sure, subordinate,
or inferior. Either way.
CLAIRE: It doesn't
mean I'm wrong.
I suppose not. But it does mean
you have to act like you're wrong.
He's panic-stricken. Yesterday,
he was young and healthy.
Today, he's mortal.
Just give him a chance to
wrap his head around that.
Dr. Kalu?
Do you think you can get me a
signed informed consent on 104?
Of course.
Thank you.
You think he's right?
I think he's my boss.
And if I have to choose between
my boss and the woman I'm screwing,
not much of a
choice. Am I right?
SHAUN: Excuse me.
Excuse me, please.
Incision should take
place two ribs down.
(ALL GASPING QUIETLY)
(AIR HISSES)
Okay, well, why the bottle?
The air will continue
to leak and accumulate
until the damage can
be properly repaired.
The tube allows
the air to get out.
The water in the bottle stops
the air from coming back in.
A home-made one-way valve.
(BOY GASPS)
He's breathing.
You saved his life.
He saved his life!
(CROWD CLAPPING)
Shaun, where are you?
Call me as soon as you can,
please. That was a mistake.
I agree. This is not
about the new doctor.
This is about you.
They're baiting you,
- and you're letting them.
- Maybe.
Maybe what? What mistake
are you talking about?
- Your shot at Andrews' nephew.
- Come on, it was funny.
It was very funny. It
was also disrespectful.
You don't show him respect. I assume
it's because you don't respect him.
You show someone respect
because you respect them
or because you're afraid of
them. I don't fit into either category.
- Well, neither do I.
- You should.
You're only in that room because
your grandfather founded this hospital.
I'm gonna pretend that this
conversation didn't take this tangent
and instead focus on something
relevant, the debate you are losing.
Here's how you win this.
You don't make it personal.
You don't make it about
you. That is what they want,
and if you give it to
them, you will lose.
(SIREN WAILING)
I need to get to San Jose
Saint Bonaventure Hospital.
That's where we're going.
Good.
SHAUN'S FATHER: How hard can it
be to just act like a normal human being?
SHAUN'S MOTHER:
He doesn't know how.
Bull! What are we
supposed to do now?
This is the third school
he's been thrown out of.
We'll find another school.
SHAUN'S FATHER: No, we won't,
'cause nothing's gonna change.
They can't handle him,
and I don't blame them
'cause obviously we
can't handle him either.
What the hell happened
this time? What happened?
You're hurting him.
What did you do? Shaun!
(SCREAMS) No!
Will you stop petting
that stupid rabbit?
It changed. The
boy's ECG changed.
It's the same, 86 BPM.
No, it used to be higher.
No, it used to
be 86. It's still 86.
It used to come up to here.
Lower amplitude means lower voltage.
What's going on?
What does it mean?
It means he's trying to
read 20-year-old equipment
while traveling in a vehicle
going 40 miles an hour.
How did you get him to sign?
JARED: I simply told him he was
either consenting or going home.
Then I gave him two forms
and told him to pick one.
DR. MELENDEZ: And you highlighted
the Release Against Medical Advice form
that mentions the possibility of
death or permanent disability?
Well done. Hand me
the Metz and a pickup.
I'm isolating the
ascending aorta.
NURSE: Vascular clamp.
CLAIRE: Hey, what is
that? Under the left atrium.
Something white. Is
that part of the lung?
DR. MELENDEZ: It's
pus. Did he have TB?
NURSE: No, he
doesn't have any...
DR. MELENDEZ: No, not
currently. Does he have a history...
JARED: When he was a
younger, he was exposed to...
DR. MELENDEZ: This is
an abscess. It's going to...
(MONITOR BEEPING RAPIDLY)
JARED: Suction and a lap
sponge. His BP's crashing.
CLAIRE: Two liters
saline wide open.
DR. MELENDEZ: Set up level
one. Two units packed cells now.
Let's get Levophed on board
and keep that MAP at 60.
Get in there with the suction.
I can't see a damn thing.
NURSE: Suction.
DR. MELENDEZ: I hope
it isn't too upsetting to him
when he hears he'd have died in
his room if we'd waited till tomorrow.
Dr. Melendez, we've got an
incoming eight-year-old male,
pneumothorax stabilized but
undetermined internal injuries.
Who do you want to catch?
DR. MELENDEZ: Claire,
I don't think we need you.
This patient is
gonna be fine now.
Eight-year-old healthy boy.
Status, post encounter
with a shattered glass sign.
- Numerous lacerations.
- Echo.
Get him set up in Trauma 3
with an EKG, full blood work,
and a pan scan.
- We need an echo. Echocardiogram.
- Who is this guy?
He helped with
first-aid at the airport.
I'm a doctor. He needs
an echocardiogram.
Where are you taking him?
To surgery. All cardiac vital
signs are within normal range.
- Do you have any ID?
- No. His heart. It's his heart.
His heart is fine.
Now, stay here.
Adam needs an echocardiogram.
No. Behave yourself, or you'll
be removed from the building.
(PANTING) Echo... Echo...
DR. MELENDEZ: What's that?
CLAIRE: A one-way valve. EMT
reports the boy suffered a pneumothorax.
DR. MELENDEZ: That is cool.
Do you think we should
do an echocardiogram?
Based on the presenting
symptoms, which give no indication
that an echocardiogram is
necessary, I'm going to answer no.
Am I missing something?
No, sir.
Knife.
DR. GLASSMAN: We don't
normally treat rabbits, especially...
This was the closest doctor
place, and it was an emergency.
DR. GLASSMAN: No, I can
see that. But even if I was a vet,
the rabbit is dead.
I'm sorry, guys.
Everything smells
different when it rains.
What do we do now?
Well, you should
bury him, I guess.
I don't know. Give
him a nice funeral.
Has he gone to heaven?
Yeah, sure. Sure. Sure, he has.
No, I don't want him to go to
heaven. I want him to be here.
This won't happen again.
It can't happen
again. He's dead.
I know that.
I mean, nothing like this is ever
going to happen to us ever again.
Because we're not going home.
We're never going home again.
We have each other,
and that's all we need.
DR. ANDREWS: A surgeon
needs to communicate,
not just information
but sympathy, empathy.
Can Dr. Murphy do that?
He can't even reliably
show up for a job interview.
Are you going to
sit here and tell us
that there were no other
equally qualified young surgeons,
surgeons without
this one's issues?
No, which is why, exactly
why, we should hire Shaun.
We should hire him because he is
qualified and because he's different.
How long ago was it that we wouldn't
hire black doctors in this hospital?
How long ago was it that we
wouldn't hire female doctors
at this hospital?
So you're comparing being
African-American or a woman
with being autistic?
Please, go on.
Okay.
The rationalization
is exactly the same.
Words like "temperament,"
and, "Oh, no.
"Oh! How are the
patients going to react?"
Aren't we judged by
how we treat people?
I don't mean as doctors.
I mean as people.
Especially those who don't have
the same advantages that we have.
We hire Shaun, and we give
hope to those people with limitations
that those limitations are
not what they think they are.
That they do have a shot.
We hire Shaun, and we
make this hospital better for it.
are better people for it.
We'd be better people
spending a lot more on
malpractice insurance.
DR. MELENDEZ: How
old is this kid again?
JARED: Eight.
DR. MELENDEZ: Sponge stick.
What was his heart
rate five minutes ago?
JARED: Eighty-six.
You sure?
JARED: Certain. He's been
a rock. It's barely changed.
DR. MELENDEZ: No, something's
changed. Something's different.
You asked earlier about an
echo? You had no medical reason,
but you asked anyway. Why?
CLAIRE: There was this weird guy,
the one that did the one-way valve.
He kept insisting that the boy
needed an echocardiogram.
- DR. MELENDEZ: He didn't say why?
- He was really weird.
(RAPID BEEPING)
CLAIRE: His blood pressure's
dropping. That makes no sense.
He's not bleeding anymore.
Everything's under control.
DR. MELENDEZ: Do an echo.
JARED: Sir, the boy's wide
open. It's gonna take a while.
Good. That'll give me time to figure
out why the hell we're doing an echo.
Dr. Browne, you're with
me. We're gonna go find
your weird guy. Keep him stable.
Why the echo?
Okay. The... The...
Okay. The... I...
Okay. I understand you think
he needs an echocardiogram.
We just don't know why.
Well, I noticed that there was
a slight reduction in the intensity
of the electrocardiogram.
The electrical flow?
I noticed that, too.
The heart rate was the same
but the amplitude dropped.
Pericardial effusion.
Reduced cardiac output.
Would stress other organs.
Causing them to shut down.
Yes.
Hold on. Yeah. We're
coming right back up.
Thank you.
They did the echo. It's
normal. No pericardial effusion.
No, it has to be. There
is no other explanation.
The echo is normal, which
means we just wasted our time.
No.
(SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY)
Okay. Hey. Come
with me. Come on.
Show them.
Again.
There.
Looks normal to me.
It's not normal. There's a concave
deformity in the right atrium.
No, there's not.
Yes, there is. It's very subtle.
Even if you are
right, that's not
where a pericardial
effusion manifests.
Not usually. But it could.
This kid was sprayed with
glass shards. Cut his jugular.
What if a piece of glass
entered his bloodstream?
It could have traveled
down the jugular vein
into the brachiocephalic vein
and onto the superior vena cava.
If it punctured the SVC, a block
could be leaking behind the heart,
restricting the heart's ability to
expand and fill during diastole,
reducing the heart's efficiency.
Lot of ifs there.
Dr. Chen,
prepare a 14-gauge
on the syringe.
All in favor of ratifying
Dr. Glassman's decision in hiring
Dr. Shaun Murphy?
All against?
Excuse me.
- Is this a medical emergency?
- No, no medical emergency.
Then you weren't
supposed to interrupt...
Yes, I know, but
you need to go online.
What? What site?
Pretty much any of them. Twitter,
YouTube, any local news site.
You saved his life.
The YouTube clip already
has over 200,000 views.
Apparently, he's
one of our doctors.
Dr. Shaun Murphy saved this boy.
The boy is in OR-2. Dr. Melendez
isn't sure if he's going to make it.
Your fiancé sure
can handle a knife.
Why did you warn me about
respecting Dr. Andrews?
What's going on?
I'm not gonna always
be here to protect you.
You think you're gonna lose?
Everybody loses eventually.
Is that your guy?
Can we get a TV?
No.
Why not?
Because we're poor,
dude. We live in a bus.
Do you think Mom
is looking for us?
No.
She loves us, but she
knows it's better this way.
I got you a present.
It's not my birthday.
I got you a present anyway.
Here.
DR. MELENDEZ: Kelly.
Dr. Browne,
you were right.
(CLAIRE EXHALES)
I don't like pickles.
I know.
I don't want pickles.
And I checked.
You saved that boy's life.
Oh, good.
His name is Adam.
Traumatic pneumothorax.
I'm hungry.
The board reconvenes
in 45 minutes.
Can you stay here
until I get back?
Okay.
He's got a serious deficit.
A child is alive today
because of that deficit.
And tomorrow, one may
be dead because of it.
I seem to remember
that when I hired you,
you weren't exactly making
the most adult decisions.
You haven't killed
anyone yet, have you?
Well, thankfully, there's a
cure for youth and stupidity,
time and experience.
(CHUCKLES) There's a
cure for stupidity? Okay.
That would be a windfall.
All Shaun has is a diagnosis.
I'd like your help. I take
it I'm not gonna get it.
Okay.
Wait.
What's the story with this kid?
Why is it so important to you?
Why not?
Because letting
things get personal
is a sure formula for
screwing things up.
I don't know.
Letting things get
personal is how we...
How we make it matter.
So are you proud
or disappointed?
Do I have to pick just one?
Hey.
You're new to town, right?
Yes.
Well, I'm sure you
have a lot of questions.
No.
You've got to be curious about
the place, about the people.
Dr. Glassman gave
me a map of the hospital,
and I got a map
of San Jose online.
Okay.
Great.
I do have one question.
Yeah.
Why were you rude to
me when we first met,
then nicer to me the
second time we met,
and now you want
to be my friend?
Which time was it that
you were pretending?
Shaun, we're ready.
The vote was clear. Why
are we reopening this?
Is it really because
of a piece of publicity?
It's because the man
just saved somebody's life.
And thank God for that,
but it doesn't change a
single thing we discussed.
DR. GLASSMAN:
Give him six months.
If he proves anything
less than excellent...
Someone less than excellent
means someone else dies.
Well, I would love to
make you happy, Doctor.
I would love to hire someone
who never, ever makes a mistake.
Unfortunately, God
already has a job.
I can accept that
he will have insights
that none of the
rest of us will have.
Can you accept that
he will make mistakes
none of the rest
of us will make?
You won't be the one
who pays the price.
If Shaun doesn't live up to
everything I know he can do,
he will be immediately released,
and I will resign my position
as president of this hospital.
We haven't heard
from Dr. Murphy yet.
Perhaps we should hear from
him before we decide his fate.
DR. GLASSMAN: Shaun.
Dr. Murphy, I'd
like you to tell us
why you want to
become a surgeon.
SHAUN: Why do I want
them to be my friends?
STEVE: Everybody
needs friends, Shaun.
It's gonna be cool, okay?
Play hide-and-seek, maybe?
- Okay.
- Tag in the warehouse.
(KIDS CHATTERING)
I told you, it's fun, right?
(SHUSHES)
Hey. You know what?
(SCREAMS)
(THUDDING)
The day that the rain
smelled like ice cream,
my bunny went to
heaven in front of my eyes.
The day that the copper
pipes in the old building
smelled like burnt food,
my brother
went to heaven
in front of my eyes.
I couldn't save them. It's sad.
Neither one had the
chance to become an adult.
They should have become adults.
They should have had
children of their own
and loved those children.
And I want to make that
possible for other people.
And I want to make a lot of money
so that I can have a television.
Dr. Murphy,
I want to be the
first to welcome you
to San Jose Saint
Bonaventure Hospital.
We're very proud to have you.
(PEOPLE CLAPPING)
DR. GLASSMAN: Shaun,
Dr. Melendez's team
is going into surgery.
I mean, if you're interested.
DR. MELENDEZ:
Got a messy field here.
Murphy.
SHAUN: Suction.
Never forget,
you're the smart one.
You can do anything.
And I'm proud of you, Shaun.
DR. MELENDEZ: Thought
you've seen many of these.
I remember my first.
I kept thinking, "It doesn't
get any better than this."
But for you, I'm afraid,
that's literally true.
You're a nice kid, and
you're obviously very smart,
but you don't belong here.
So, as long as you're
part of my team,
this is all you're ever
going to be doing, suction.
SHAUN: I saw a lot of
surgeons in medical school.
You're much better than them.
I have a lot to learn from you.
You're very arrogant.
Do you think that helps
you be a good surgeon?
Does it hurt you as a person?
Is it worth it?
(MUSIC PLAYING)
api.OpenSubtitles.org is deprecated, please
implement REST API from OpenSubtitles.com